Guide to the Johan Kugelberg hip hop collection, circa 1975-1985, 2008.
Kugelberg, Johan hip hop collection,
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Johan Kugelberg hip hop collection, circa 1975-1985, 2008.
8021
Johan, Kugelberg
22 cubic feet.
Audio Recordings, Memorabilia, Photographs, Printed Materials
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
The collection documents the origins of hip-hop as music, culture and community in the Bronx, NY, and its influence on the history of music, art, performance, and activism in America during the final third of the 20th century and beyond.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Contains nearly 1,000 recordings (primarily LP records), textile art, books and magazines, and more than 500 original party and club flyers designed by Buddy Esquire and others. The collection documents the origins of hip-hop as music, culture and community in the Bronx, NY, and its influence on the history of music, art, performance, and activism in America during the final third of the 20th century and beyond.
Also, t-shirts, tote bag, and other memorabilia documenting the 2008 Hip Hop Conference and Celebration at Cornell; and a poster for Spike Lee's motion picture "Do the Right Thing" (1989).
74 candid hip hop photos depicting various music events, record signings and performances - includes Raandu Avion, Brandy, Missy Elliott, Mary J. Blige, DMX and Wyclef Jean (2001).
SUBJECTS
Names:
Kugelberg, Johan,; Conzo, Joe, Jr.; Afrika Bambaataa, 1957-
Subjects:
Hip-hop.; Hip-hop -- History. -- United States; Rap (Music); Hip-hop; Rap (Music); Rap musicians.; Hip-hop -- New York.; Rap (Music) -- New York.; Graffiti.; Street art.; Break dancing.; Break dancing -- History.; Disc jockeys.; Break dancing; Disc jockeys; Graffiti; Hip-hop; Rap (Music); Rap musicians; Social history; Street art
Places:
Bronx (New York, N.Y.); Bronx (New York, N.Y.) -- Social conditions -- 20th century.; New York (State) -- New York; New York (State) -- Bronx; United States
Form and Genre Terms:
Cross-cultural studies; History
INFORMATION FOR USERS
NOTES
Books, LPs, and poster associated with the collection are cataloged individually.
This collection was previously titled Cornell University Library hip hop collection
Joe Conzo Jr. photographs and related material previously in boxes 25-31 have been moved to the Joe Conzo, Jr. photographs and ephemera collection, #8091
Spelling of artist names is, in most cases, as it appears on the album, this leads to some discrepancies.
SERIES LIST
Series I. Sound Recordings
Boxes 1-24, 46-47
Box 1 - LPs - SR 19-63
Box 2 - LPs - SR 64-112
Box 3 - LPs - SR 113-154
Box 4 - LPs - SR 155-205
Box 5 - LPs - SR 206-259
Box 6 - LPs - SR 260-310
Box 7 - LPs - SR 311-357
Box 8 - LPs - SR 358-412
Box 9 - LPs - SR 413-465
Box 10 - LPs - SR 466-520
Box 11 - LPs - SR 521-573
Box 12 - LPs - SR 574-623
Box 13 - LPs - SR 624-676
Box 14 - LPs - SR 677-723
Box 15 - LPs - SR 724-775
Box 16 - LPs - SR 776-827
Box 17 - LPs - SR 828-851
Box 18 - LPs - Duplicates of some items from Box 1-17
Box 19 - 45s and 7" records - SR 852-922, includes duplicates
Box 20 - CDs - CD 360-398
Box 21 - CDs - CD 399-414, includes duplicates
Boxes 22-24 - Expansion space
Boxes 46-47 - CDs - CD 1470-1510 - Prints created by Cornell Library’s digital reproduction lab in 2014 for Joe Conzo’s exhibition at the Rock and Roll Hall of fame
Series II. Videos
Shelved separately
Series III. Party and Club Fliers
Boxes 32-37
Subseries III.a. Major Club Venues
Subseries IV.b. Other Clubs and Venues
Subseries IV.c. Oversized Fliers
Subseries IV.d. Original Flyer Art
Subseries IV.e. Buddy Esquire Flier Working Files
Series V. Textiles and original art
Boxes 41, 42, 45
Series VI. Born in the Bronx
Boxes 35, 40, 43, and mapcase folder
Series VII. Miscellaneous
Boxes 35, 40, and mapcase folder
CONTAINER LIST
- Series I. Sound Recordings (1-24)
  These recordings have individual records in the library catalog. The individual record in the catalog contains additional information not included here.
  - LPs - SR 19-63 (Box 1)
    - Big Apple rappin' Vol. 1, The early days of hip-hop culture in New York City, 1979-1982 Performed by: Various performers, 2006; SR-19 (Box 1)
      Publisher: Soul Jazz Records
      Track listing: Spoonin' rap (Spoonie Gee) (6:58) -- Sure shot (Xanadu) (5:26) -- How we gonna make the black nation rise (Brother D with Collective Effort) (5:51) -- Rapping dub style (General Echo) (4:13) -- Catch the beat (T Ski Valley) (8:33) -- Dancing heart (Universal 2) (7:52) -- Funkbox party (Masterdon Committee) (6:58) -- Weekend (Cold Crush Brothers) (5:35).
    - Big Apple rappin' Vol. 2, The early days of hip-hop culture in New York City, 1979-1982 Performed by: Various performers, 2006; SR-20 (Box 1)
      Track listing: Big Apple rappin' (Spyder D) (10:18) -- Mr. Q (DJ Style) (5:04) -- Fly Guys rap (The Fly Guys) (7:41) -- Get the party jumpin' (Solo Sound) (6:17) -- Rock the beat (The Jamaica Girls) (6:23) -- Standing on the top (Super 3) (6:52) -- Are you ready (TJ Swann, Peewee Mel & Barry B (7:31) -- The ultimate rap (Nice and Nasty 3) (9:17).
    - Breakdancing / produced by Don Oriolo and Juergen Korduletsch Performed by: Various performers, 1984; SR-21 (Box 1)
      Publisher: Columbia
      Track listing: Buffalo gals / Malcolm McLaren -- Rockit / Herbie Hancock -- I wonder if I take you home / Lisa-Lisa and Cult Jam -- Trommeltanz / George Kranz -- It's like that / Run-D.M.C. -- I want it to be real / John Rocca -- Drive me crazy / Kid Savage -- One more shot / C-Bank -- White lines (don't do it) / Grand Master Melle Mel -- Hey you (the Rocksteady Crew) / The Rocksteady Crew.
    - Electric breakdance Performed by: Various performers, 1984; SR-22 (Box 1)
      Publisher: Dominion Records
      Track listing: Jam on it (Newcleus) -- Clock on the wall (Double Vision) -- Magic's wand (Whodini) -- You're the one for me (D Train) -- Electric kingdom (Twilight 22) -- White lines (don't do it) (Grandmaster Flash & Melle Mel -- Play that beat Mr. D.J. (G.L.O.B.E. & Whiz Kid) -- Rockit (B.T. & The City Slickers) -- It's like that (Run-D.M.C.).
    - Live convention "81" / various artists Performed by: Wheels of Steel, Cut Creators, Cheif's [sic] Rockers, and others, 1981; SR-23 (Box 1)
      Publisher: Ol' Skool Flava
      Track listing: Not listed
    - All the way: Live in '82 / Cold Crush Brothers Performed by: Cold Crush Brothers, 1994; SR-24 (Box 1)
      Publisher: Tuff City Records
      Track listing: Live in Connecticut (15:45) -- It's like that y'all (3:35) -- It's us (The Cold Crush) (3:35) -- Freestylin' (7:30).
    - Rhythm method Performed by: Various performers, 1988; SR-25 (Box 1)
      Publisher: PolyGram
      Track listing: House arrest (The beat is the law) (Krush) -- The payback mix (Keep on doing what you're doing but make it funky) (James Brown) -- Work me down (extended version) (Laura Hunter) -- Oh l'amour (Dollar) -- Bass (How low can you go) (Ragamuffin remix) (Simon Harris) -- Hypnotize (12" house mix) (Taste-T-Lips) -- Don't treat me like this (dance remix) (Anita) -- Mr. Manic and Sister Cool (Cool mix) (Shakatak).
    - Wild style Performed by: Various performers, 1983; SR-26 (Box 1)
      Publisher: Animal Records
      Track listing: Wild style theme rap 1 (Grand Master Caz and Chris Stein) -- M.C. battle: The Chief Rocker Busy Bee v.s. [sic] Lil Rodney Cee with D.J. Grand Wizard Theodore -- Basketball throwdown: The Cold Crush Bros. v.s. The Fantastic Freaks -- Fantastic Freaks at the Dixie -- Military cut-scratch mix (turntables, Grand Wizard Theodore and Kevie Kev Rockwell) -- Cold Crush Bros. at the Dixie -- Stoop rap (Double Trouble, Rodney Cee, K.K. Rockwell) -- Double Trouble at the amphitheatre (Rodney Cee, K.K. Rockwell, D.J. Stevie Steve) -- Wild style subway rap 2 (Grand Master Caz and Chris Stein) -- The Chief Rocker Busy Bee, D.J. AJ at the amphitheatre -- Gangbusters scratch mix (turntables, Grand Wizard Theodore and Kevie Kev Rockwell) -- Rammellzee and Shock Dell at the amphitheatre with the Grand Mixer DST.
    - Wild style original soundtrack Performed by: Various performers, 1998; SR-27 (Box 1)
      Publisher: Beyongolia
      Track listing: Military cut: scratch mix by DJ Grand Wizard Theodore -- MC battle: Busy Bee vs. Rodney Cee -- Basketball throwdown: The Cold Crush Brothers vs. Fantastic Freaks -- Fantastic Freaks at the Dixie -- Subway theme: scratch mix by DJ Grand Wizard Theodore -- Cold Crush Brothers at the Dixie -- Busy Bee's limo rap -- Cuckoo clocking -- Stoop rap (Double Trouble (Rodney Cee & KK Rockwell)) -- Double Trouble at the Ampitheatre -- South Bronx subway rap -- Street rap / by Busy Bee -- Busy Bee at the Ampitheatre -- Fantastic Freaks at the Ampitheatre -- Gangbusters: scratch mix by DJ Grand Wizard Theodore -- Rammellzee & Shockdell at the Ampitheatre -- Down by law (with Fab 5 Freddy).
    - Best of Enjoy! Records Performed by: Various performers, 1989; SR-28 (Box 1)
      Publisher: Enjoy! Records; Marketed and distributed by Hot Productions
      Track listing: Superappin (Grandmaster Flash & Furious Five) -- Love rap (Spoonie Gee & The Treacherous Three) -- Body rock (The Treacherous Three with Kool Moe Dee) -- At the party (The Treacherous Three with Kool Moe Dee) -- It's magic (Fearless Four) -- Move with the groove (The Disco Four) -- Funk box party (The Masterdon Committee) -- Feel the heart beat (The Treacherous Three with Kool Moe Dee) -- Just having fun (Doug E. Fresh) -- The new rap language (The Treacherous Three) -- Rappin and rocking the house (Funky Four + One) -- Rockin' it (The Fearless Four).
    - Enjoy! Performed by: Various performers, 1982; SR-29 (Box 1)
      Publisher: New York Connexion
      Track listing: Rockin' it (The Fearless Four) -- Rappin' and rockin' the house (The Funky Four + 1) -- Shake 'em up (Higher Ground) -- The body rock (The Treacherous Three) -- Love rap (Spoonie Gee) -- Gonna get you hot (Masterdon Committee) -- Enjoy with me (Midnight Blue).
    - Super rap: [original rap & hip hop from Harlem's P & P Records] Performed by: Various performers, 2002; SR-30 (Box 1)
      Publisher: P & P Records: Manufactured & distributed by LandSpeed Records
      Track listing: Fly Guy rap (Fly Guy) -- Boogie feeling rap (Sweet G) -- Death rap (Margo's Kool Out Crew) -- Rhapazooty blue (Sicle Cell & Rhapazooty) -- Scoopy rap (Scoopy) -- Super Jay love theme (Super Jay) -- Tricky tee rap (Troy Rainey) -- Patty Duke (Cloud One) -- Sweet Naomi rap (Naomi) -- Smooth talk (Mr. Fox) -- Gangster rock (Land Of The Hits Orchestra) -- Willie rap (Willie Wood & Willie Wood Crew)
    - Old school classics Performed by: Various performers, 1989; SR-31 (Box 1)
      Track listing: Rock it out (the Maximus Three) -- Can I get a soul clap, fresh out of the pack (the Grand Wizard Theodore & the Fantastic Five) -- Smurf across the surf (the Micronawts) -- Yvette (the Cold Crush Brothers) -- The adventures of super rhymes (Jimmy Spicer) -- Catch the beat (T-Ski Valley).
    - Disco party freaks: 12 smokin' joints Performed by: Various performers, 1980; SR-32 (Box 1)
      Publisher: Paul Wesley Records
      Track listing: Rock your baby (George McRae) -- Supernatural thing (Ben E. King) -- Express (B.T. Express) -- Soul makossa (Mighty Tom Cats) -- Kung fu fighting (Carl Douglas) -- Breakdown-part one (Rufus Thomas) -- Can't get enough (Barry White) -- Skin tight (Ohio Players) -- It's your thing (The Isley Brothers) -- Harlem (Bill Withers) -- Respect yourself (The Staple Singers) -- Philadelphia (B.B. King).
    - Live convention '82 Performed by: Various performers, 1982; SR-33 (Box 1)
      Publisher: Disco Wax Records
    - Now rap's what I call music! Performed by: Various performers, 1989; SR-34 (Box 1)
      Publisher: Polygram
      Track listing: The payback mix (James Brown) -- Back by popular demand (the 12" version) (Kurtis Blow) -- My mike sounds nice (Salt-n-Pepa) -- Pump up the volume (12" U.S. version) (M/A/R/R/S) -- Wipeout (Wave 1 version) (Fat Boys) -- Bass/How low can you go (extended version (Simon Harris) -- House arrest (The beat is the law) (Krush) -- Pump me up (White Boys) -- Little Walter (2 Tuff radio mix) (Tony! Toni! Tone´!) -- Rap around the clock (The Housemartins).
    - Ultimate lessons Performed by: Various performers, 1989; SR-35 (Box 1)
      Publisher: Starchild
      Track listing: Lesson 1 (Double Dee + Steinski) (5:23) -- Lesson 4: The radio (5:30); Lesson 6: The lecture (original unedited version) (Cut Chemist) -- Lesson 2 (4:23); Lesson 3 (4:57) (Double Dee + Steinski) -- Lesson 4 (DJ Shadow) (7:46) -- Live lesson A (Cut Chemist + Shortkut) (5:30) -- Live lesson B (DJ Shadow, Cut Chemist, + Shortkut) (11:42) -- Live lesson C (DJ Shadow) (20:17)
    - Psychedelic Furs Performed by: Psychedelic Furs, 1980; SR-36 (Box 1)
      Publisher: CBS
      Track listing: India -- Sister Europe -- Imitation of Christ -- Fall -- Pulse -- We love you -- Wedding song -- Blacks/Radio -- Flowers.
    - Slim Gaillard rides again Performed by: Slim Gaillard, guitar, 1976; SR-37 (Box 1)
      Publisher: MCA Records
      Track listing: How high the moon--Slim's cee--One minute of flamenco for three minutes--Chicken rhythm--I love you--Oh, lady be good--I don't stand a ghost of a chance with you--Little girl--Tall and slim--My blue heaven--Thunderbird--Walkin' & cookin' blues--Sukiyaki cha cha--Don't blame me--Darktown strutters ball--I'm gonna sit right down and write myself a letter.
    - Joseph Papp presents Runaways / written, composed, and directed by Elizabeth Swados Performed by: Elizabeth Swados, 1978; SR-38 (Box 1)
      Track listing: Where do people go -- Every now and then -- Minnesota Strip; Song of a child prostitute -- Find me a hero -- The undiscovered son -- No lullabies for Luis -- We are not strangers -- The basketball song -- Let me be a kid -- Revenge song; Enterprise -- Lullaby from baby to baby -- Sometimes -- Where are those people who did "Hair" -- To the dead of family wars -- Lonesome of the road; Let me be a kid (reprise).
    - Beatle rap Performed by: Qworymen, 1982; SR-39 (Box 1)
      Publisher: Erika Records: Rhino
    - Twas the night before Christmas; Christmas rappin' / Billy Jackson and the Citizen Band featuring Little Rodney C Performed by: Billy Jackson, 1982; SR-40 (Box 1)
      Publisher: Dimensional Music
    - Femme Fatales Performed by: Femme Fatales, 1987; SR-41 (Box 1)
      Publisher: Stupid Records
      Track listing: I need a date -- Leader of the pack rap.
    - Hip hop bommi bop; Hip hop bommi bop bop / The Incredible T H Scratchers starring Freddy Love Performed by: Incredible T H Scratchers, 1983; SR-42 (Box 1)
      Publisher: EMI
    - UN rap song; Dance to your TV Performed by: Stew Lane and the Untouchables, 1980; SR-43 (Box 1)
      Publisher: Regular Stars Pub.
      Track listing: U.N. rap song -- Dance to your T.V.
    - Rap rap music; Rap attack; Rap attack remix / Graffiti Performed by: Graffiti, 1979; SR-44 (Box 1)
      Publisher: RKM
    - Rap call you (vocal); Rap call you (instrumental) / Graffiti, Performed by: Europ Express, 1980; SR-45 (Box 1)
    - Another sad song; It ain't New York; Discombobulatorbubalator / MC Breeze Performed by: MC Breeze, 1980; SR-46 (Box 1)
      Publisher: Breeze Records
    - Roller dancing for fun & fitness Performed by: [Unknown], 1980; SR-47 (Box 1)
      Publisher: Gateway Records
    - Let us entertain you (vocal); Let us entertain you (instrumental); B boy down mix / Bambi and Mr. Freeze Performed by: Bambi and Mr. Freeze, 1980; SR-48 (Box 1)
      Publisher: Jackie Jack Records
    - Hand bone/The auction / Frankie Smith Performed by: Frankie Smith, vocals; with acc, 1981; SR-49 (Box 1)
      Publisher: P.B.I. Records
    - Man with the master plan; The cowboy / Billy Lamont & the Unn Band Performed by: Billy Lamont, 1980; SR-50 (Box 1)
      Publisher: Law-Ton Records
    - Cop bop (disco mix); Cop bop (radio mix); Cop bop (instrumental) / Portable Patrol Performed by: Portable Patrol, 1983; SR-51 (Box 1)
      Publisher: Atoll Music; Distribuzione Dischi Ricordi
      Track listing:
    - I'm Little Ray Rapper; Get that future punk / Little Ray Rapper Performed by: Little Ray Rapper, 1981; SR-52 (Box 1)
      Publisher: First American
      Track listing: I'm Little Ray Rapper -- Get that future punk.
    - O que toca nos bailes Vol. II Performed by: [Unknown], ca.1980; SR-53 (Box 1)
      Publisher: Miami Hip-hop
      Track listing: Rap do dende -- Rap da consiencia -- Rap do sangue bom (ta´ ligado) -- Mont. do bambole -- 550 km (pare um pouquinho -- Rastafare.
    - Meet me at the go-go Performed by: Hot, Cold Sweat, 1980; SR-54 (Box 1)
      Publisher: D.E.T.T. Records
      Track listing: Meet me at the go-go (vocal) -- Meet me at the go-go (instrumental).
    - B boy chronicles continued Chapter 2, Geniuses at work Performed by: The Saxon Scoundrels, 2003; SR-55 (Box 1)
      Publisher: B Boy Beats & Pieces Lmtd.
    - Ice arcade / the Chilly Kids Performed by: Chilly Kids, 1983; SR-56 (Box 1)
      Publisher: Sugar Hill Records
      Track listing: Ice arcade (vocal) -- Ice arcade (Instrumental).
    - You're my candy sweet / Fatback Performed by: Fatback, 1974; SR-57 (Box 1)
      Publisher: Spring
    - This is radio clash; Outside broadcast Performed by: The Clash, 1981; SR-58 (Box 1)
      Publisher: Epic
      Track listing: This is radio clash -- Outside broadcast.
    - Get fresh get fresh (break dance) / PC Crew Performed by: P.CCrew, 1983; SR-59 (Box 1)
      Publisher: Factory Beat Records
      Track listing: A. Get fresh get fresh (break dance) (5:03) -- B. Get fresh get fresh (break dance) (4:00).
    - Fly guy / Pebblee-Poo Performed by: Pebblee-Poo, 1985; SR-60 (Box 1)
      Publisher: Profile
      Track listing: A fly guy -- A fly guy (instrumental).
    - I wanna play; Blow some funk this way / The Pied Piper of Funkingham Performed by: Pied Piper of Funkingham, 1981; SR-61 (Box 1)
      Publisher: Chocolate Cholly's
    - Rock it baby / P-Man Performed by: P-Man, ca.1980; SR-62 (Box 1)
      Publisher: P-Man Music; Bound Sound Records
      Track listing: Rock it baby -- Rock it baby (scratch mix).
    - Happy song or dance; Pleasure boys / Visage Performed by: Visage, 1980; SR-63 (Box 1)
      Publisher: Rated "X" Records
  - LPs - SR 64-112 (Box 2)
    - At the fever Performed by: Various performers, 1986; SR-64 (Box 2)
      Publisher: Fever Records
      Track listing: Games people play (Sweet G) -- Starski live at the Disco Fever; Do the right thing (Love-bug Starski) -- I'm gonna rock you (Gigolette) -- School girl crush (Nayobe) -- You've gotta believe (Love-bug Starski) -- Bust this rhyme (M.C. Chill) -- Games females play (Gigolette) -- Waiting for your love (Sweet G) -- Please don't go (Nayobe).
    - Breakdance Performed by: Various performers, 1984; SR-65 (Box 2)
      Publisher: K-tel
      Track listing: Wheels of steel (Grandmaster Flash & the Furious Five) -- Electric kingdom (Twilight 22) -- Pop goes my love (Freeez) -- Rockit (B.T. & the City Slickers) -- Joystick (Dazz Band) -- Tour de France (10-Speed) -- Electric shocks; Space walk action; Rap-o-tition; Scratch walk; Shake your arm up and down with the boogie speed; Boogie head; Let electro beat make your body move (Alex & the City Crew) -- The New York City breakers (Michael Holman; with vocals by Us Girls).
    - Rapp attack Vol. 1 Performed by: Various performers, ca. 1981; SR-66 (Box 2)
      Publisher: Posse Records
      Track listing: King Tim III (personality jock) (Fatback) -- Money (dollar bill y'all) (Jimmy Spicer) -- Magic's message (Mr. Magic) -- Rockin' it (M.C. Flex & The F.B.I. Crew) -- Please stay (Fatback & Gerry Bledsoe) -- The alarm (double XX rated, not for airplay) (The Hawk) -- Rap '81 (Millie Jackson).
    - Rap Performed by: Various performers, 1981; SR-67 (Box 2)
      Publisher: Sugar Hill
      Track listing: The birthday party (Grandmaster Flash & The Furious Five) -- That's the joint (Funky 4 plus 1) -- Baby let's rap now (The Moments) -- To the beath [sic; death] (y'all) (Lady B.) -- Spoon'in rap (Spoonie Gee).
    - Street beats Performed by: Grandmaster Flash, Melle Mel, Treacherous Three, West Street Mob, Duke Bootee, Sugar Hill Gang, Jocko, the Furious Five, Fine Quality featuring Cuz, Crash Crew, Kevie Kev, and Farrari, 1984; SR-68 (Box 2)
      Track listing: White lines (don't, don't do it) -- Yes we can-can -- Break dancin', electric boogie -- Message II -- Kick it live from 9 to 5 -- Everybody's uptight -- New York, New York -- Aah dance -- We are known as the emcees (we turn the party's out) -- The adventures of Grandmaster Flash on the wheels of steel. 8th wonder; Birthday party; Monster jam; Good times; Another one bites the dust; Rapture -- All night long -- Simon says dance.
    - Ego Trip's the big playback Performed by: Various performers, 2000; SR-69 (Box 2)
      Publisher: Rawkus Records
      Track listing: Holy war (live) / Divine Force -- My mic is on fire / Lord Shafiyq -- Marley Marl scratch / Marley Marl (featuring Mc Shan) -- Get retarded / MC Ez & Troup -- Get down Grandmaster / Grandmaster Caz -- Step up front / Positive K -- This cut's got flavor / Latee -- Droppin' it / The Bizzie Boyz -- I'm not playing / Ultimate Force -- Do it! Do it! / The Alliance -- Brooklyn blew up the bridge / MC Mitchski -- Beat bop / Rammelzee vs. K-Rob.
    - Mr. Magic's rap attack Performed by: Various performers, 1985; SR-70 (Box 2)
      Track listing: Walk this way / Run-D.M.C. -- It's my beat / Sweet Tee and Jazzy Joyce -- Coast to coast / Word of mouth featuring D.J. Cheese -- Eric B. is president / Eric B. featuring Rakam -- Delancey Street / Dana dame -- I can't wait (To rock the mike) / Spyder-D featuring D.J. Doc -- Girls ain't nothing but trouble / D.J. Jazzy Jeff and Fresh Prince -- Triple M bass / Worse 'em --Inspector gadget / The kartoon Krew -- Get off my tip! / The masterdon committee -- Drag rap / The shadows -- Together forever (Krush-groove 4) / Run-D.M.C.
    - Old school: the big break rapper party Performed by: Various performers, 1980; SR-71 (Box 2)
      Publisher: Sweet Georgia Peach Records
      Track listing: A scoopy rap (Scoopy) -- Family rap (Family) -- Patty Duke (Cloud One) -- Johnson jumping (Johnson Product) -- Fresh female (Roller Rooster) -- Dance freak (Chain Reaction) -- Spoonin' rap (Spoonin' Gee) -- Woody rap (Woody Wood & Wood Crew) -- Santa's rap party (Super J) -- It's rough (Imperial III).
    - Uptown disco juggernaut Performed by: Various performers, 2004; SR-72 (Box 2)
      Publisher: Octipi Records
      Track listing: New York apple jack (Scott Davis) -- Flying high (Cloud One) -- Got to have your love (Clyde Alexander) -- The groove I'm in (Florence Miller) -- The guardian angel is watching us (Golden Flamingo Orchestra) -- 24 hours (Lanier).
    - Gimmie what you got; Love me, love me not / MC's of Rap Performed by: MC's of Rap, 1980; SR-73 (Box 2)
      Publisher: Rap Records
    - Fresh Freddy presents B Boy stance Performed by: Various performers, 2002; SR-74 (Box 2)
      Publisher: Strut
      Track listing: Coolin' on the ave (Freddy B & The Mighty Mic Masters feat. Captain G Whiz) -- Bounce, rock, skateroll (Trickeration) -- Drop method (Majestic Productions -- Monster rock (Something Anything) -- Def jam (Jazzy Jay) -- Juice Crew dis (Cool C) -- TSOB (Master Jay & Michael Dee) -- Standing on the top (Super 3) -- Techno scratch (Knights of the Turntables) -- Advance (Scott La Rock & The Celebrity Three) -- Human beat box (Disco Three)
    - Third unheard: Connecticut Hip Hop 1979-1983 Performed by: Various performers, 2004; SR-75 (Box 2)
      Publisher: Stones Throw Records; Distributed by Caroline Distribution